STEPHEN VERGARA

SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT ENGINEER

◆ SEATTLE, 98107, UNITED STATES

◆ (312) 806-2080

• DETAILS •

1501 NW 56th St, Apt 410 Seattle, 98107 United States (312) 806-2080 sverg84@gmail.com

• LINKS •

LinkedIn

GitHub

Personal Website

• SKILLS •

HTML & CSS

React

GraphQL

TypeScript

Sass

User Compassion & Empathy

Design Patterns

PROFILE

Software developer with three years of React, web development, and asynchronous programming. An expert in visual and web design interested in evolving and complex user experiences. Key achievements: optimized p75 page load time by 3.2 seconds; modernized query architecture for 100% privacy safety; rebuilt server and client-side implementation of data tables, reducing start-to-finish wait times by 4 seconds on average while implementing 3 new features.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Software Engineer at Meta Platforms, Inc., Seattle, WA

July 2020 — May 2023

- Optimized page load performance by 70% through GraphQL query optimization and JavaScript code-splitting
- Orchestrated weekly meetings with a team of 12 designers, data scientists, and program managers to prototype UX design for UI features of a new internal tool
- Overhauled team's rendering architecture from requirements to deployment, enforcing 100% security while reducing query time by an average of 2 seconds
- Collaborated with content designers on the curation and moderation of 3000+ content strings across the team's 3 products
- Mentored an intern and new full-time employees through meetings and pair programming sessions, leading all mentees to find teams/projects in 6 weeks with confidence in building web applications

★ PROJECTS

Personal Website

- Implemented a responsive and scalable interactive page, loading a seamless experience in less than 1 second for screens ranging from under 768 pixels to over 1200 pixels in width
- Modified Node.js configuration to uphold the latest ES6 standards
- Deployed to GitHub Pages via NPM, Yarn, and Webpack with a bundle size of 4.8 MB
- Researched Sass and TypeScript to integrate a range of technologies with 100% type safety and dynamic styling

URL Shortener

- Engineered a FastAPI application to shorten a given URL using a PostgreSQL server and random key generation with 100% uniqueness
- Integrated program into Google Chrome as a web extension on right-click within 1 week after the project's start

INTERNSHIPS

Software Engineer Intern at Meta Platforms, Inc., Seattle, WA

May 2019 — August 2019

- Built a monitoring framework for network packet failures with C++ and Python, catching over 500 total and 60 high-priority signals by summer's end
- Designed and deployed an interactive web page with a 2-second load time via PHP
- Pioneered front-end feature for agile, ambiguous back-end project in final 2 weeks of internship
- Yielded an 85% increase in coverage through extensive CI/CD testing

EDUCATION

B.S. in Computer Science, University of Michigan, Ann Arbor

September 2016 — May 2020

Gained initial UI skills through introductions to HCI models, frameworks such as Vue, and functional programming languages (e.g. OCaml, Rust)